<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://sysbio.org.ua/ua/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://sysbio.org.ua/ua/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-06-28T10:59:25-05:00</updated><id>https://sysbio.org.ua/feed.xml</id><title type="html">sysbio</title><subtitle>Systems Biology lab at IMBG, Kyiv, Ukraine.</subtitle><entry xml:lang="ua"><title type="html">Літнє студентське дистанційне стажування 2022</title><link href="https://sysbio.org.ua/ua/opportunities/2022/05/26/kau-summer-school.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Літнє студентське дистанційне стажування 2022" /><published>2022-05-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-05-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://sysbio.org.ua/opportunities/2022/05/26/kau-summer-school</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sysbio.org.ua/opportunities/2022/05/26/kau-summer-school.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="-літнє-студентське-дистанційне-стажування-2022-інформаційний--листок--2">🔊 Літнє студентське дистанційне стажування 2022. Інформаційний  листок № 2</h1>

<p><img align="right" src="/assets/img/posts/2022-05-26-kau-summer-school.png" width="40%" />
People are the key to successful software. IRIS-HEP aims to promote the development of advanced research software skills by providing opportunities for undergraduate and graduate students to connect with mentors within the larger High Energy Physics (HEP) and Computational/Data Science community. At the same time, we aim to promote software as a collaborative activity and encourage collaborations which engage individuals in ways that maximize their potential and their potential impact on the community.</p>

<p>This is the application form for the IRIS-HEP Ukrainians Fellows program - Summer Student Internship 2022 (organized through Kiev Academic University, Kyiv, Ukraine, but not limited to students from that university).</p>

<p>👉For those who are interested in the Summer Internship 2022! Please enter additional information and information about your programming skills in the Google form.
This information is needed to find 2022 mentors for the Summer Internship participants who will offer projects of interest to you, and funding for scholarships.</p>

<p>For more information, see the following website: <a href="https://iris-hep.org/fellows.html">https://iris-hep.org/fellows.html</a></p>

<p>In this application form, you will need to provide the following information:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Full name, email address, name of your university and your current or planned major and/or area of study.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>A resume/CV (in pdf format) with contact information.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>A short essay (in the text form) describing your interest in the internship program maximum 1 page. For example, you may wish to expand on 3 or 4 topics from the following list: your background, your skills, and strengths;  what software, computing or scientific topics appeal to you; previous research experience, if any; what you may want to pursue as a future career; and what benefits you would like to gain from this program.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>[Optional] The full name and email address of a reference. This is optional. Ideally it would be someone with whom you have interacted during studies or other your experience (e.g. a course or a previous research activity). You should contact the person in advance to confirm that they will write a letter for you and simply provide their name/email. After you submit this application form, we will contact them to request the letter.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>If you have any questions, write to e-mail kau@kau.edu.ua (please write in Subject: Summer Student Internship Program 2022).
Link to the <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSevNJbaFLCFzAelrgiqie9_BL3iZ-7zDXzLmbv0DUuKdqjRCA/viewform">form</a></p>]]></content><author><name>Alina Frolova</name></author><category term="opportunities" /><category term="all" /><category term="opportunities" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Для тих хто зацікавився Літнім стажуванням у КАУ!]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="ua"><title type="html">Request form for Ukrainian researchers interested to get remote research position</title><link href="https://sysbio.org.ua/ua/standwithukraine/2022/03/01/remote-positions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Request form for Ukrainian researchers interested to get remote research position" /><published>2022-03-01T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-03-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://sysbio.org.ua/standwithukraine/2022/03/01/remote-positions</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sysbio.org.ua/standwithukraine/2022/03/01/remote-positions.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="request-form-for-ukrainian-researchers-interested-to-get-remote-research-position">Request form for Ukrainian researchers interested to get remote research position</h1>

<p><img align="right" src="/assets/img/posts/2022-03-01-remote-positions.png" width="40%" /></p>

<p><br />
The war made huge adjustments to today’s science of Ukraine. It became impossible to stay in laboratories all the time; the science funding has even been reduced.<br />
Many Ukrainian scholars remain confined in the country, so they need different types of remote opportunities.</p>

<p>That is why the <strong>SisBioUa</strong> team is working on creating opportunities for Ukrainian scientists: both on-site and remote ones.
<br />
<br /></p>

<h4 id="to-help-us-and-you-take-the-following-steps-that-will-facilitate-the-progress">To help us and you, take the following steps that will facilitate the progress:</h4>
<ol>
  <li>Sign the petition to open remote positions for Ukrainian refugee scholars:<br />
<a href="https://www.change.org/p/universities-open-remote-positions-for-ukrainian-refugee-scholars">https://www.change.org/p/universities-open-remote-positions-for-ukrainian-refugee-scholars</a></li>
  <li>If you are a researcher who is relocating or already relocated to another country, please see these resources:<br />
 <a href="https://github.com/bgruening/awesome-ukraine-support/blob/main/README.md">https://github.com/bgruening/awesome-ukraine-support/blob/main/README.md</a></li>
  <li>Fill the questionnare:<br />
 <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeMvof14FSYAABpPc5PhOFo5RFBctDEGwJFFbfn6Dj1CFb3gA/viewform">https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeMvof14FSYAABpPc5PhOFo5RFBctDEGwJFFbfn6Dj1CFb3gA/viewform</a>
    <ul>
      <li><em>Note:</em> <em>Your personal information including name and email won’t be transferred to third parties without your consent.</em></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>We are working on mechanisms to make it happen but it is in progress as legal background for this kind of employment abroad is not developed for academic institutions. We will contact you in case we have questions or updates.</p>

<p>If you were invited for on-site position but cannot accept this offer because you cannot or do not wish to leave Ukraine, please tell them about this activity and feel free to include me into the loop - maybe by that time we will have some updates.</p>

<p>If you have any questions or ideas please contact Nika Romero nika.biph@gmail.com or Alina Frolova a.o.frolova@imbg.org.ua.</p>]]></content><author><name>Alina Frolova</name></author><category term="standwithukraine" /><category term="all" /><category term="standwithukraine" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Questionnaire on the possibilities of remote positions due to the war]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="ua"><title type="html">KAU Data Science School-2022</title><link href="https://sysbio.org.ua/ua/opportunities/2022/01/14/kau-school.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KAU Data Science School-2022" /><published>2022-01-14T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-01-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://sysbio.org.ua/opportunities/2022/01/14/kau-school</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sysbio.org.ua/opportunities/2022/01/14/kau-school.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="kau-data-science-school">KAU Data Science School</h1>

<p><img src="/assets/img/posts/2022-01-14-kau-school.png" alt="KAU SCHOOL" title="Title" width="50%" /></p>

<p>З радістю повідомляємо, що KAU Data Science School повертається!</p>

<p>Цього року Школа з машинного навчання та науки про дані KAU Data Science School відбудеться вже вчетверте та об’єднає ще більшу кількість крутих спікерів, теорії, а найголовніше – практичних занять з реальними кейсами!</p>

<p>Дати KAU Data Science School у 2022 році: <em>12 та 13 березня.</em></p>

<h2 id="про-школу-kau-data-science-school">Про школу KAU Data Science School</h2>

<p>Школа з машинного навчання та науки про дані KAU Data Science School-2022 – ініціатива студентів магістратури Кафедри математики (при Інституті математики НАНУ) Київського академічного університету.</p>

<h2 id="у-рамках-школи-учасники-мають-можливість">У рамках Школи учасники мають можливість:</h2>
<ul>
  <li>зануритися у тематику “Data Science”, “Big Data”, “Machine Learning” та “Computer Vision”, що все більше привертає увагу студентської молоді та науковців у сучасному світі;</li>
  <li>відвідати лекції найдосвідченіших представників наукового світу і приватних компаній;</li>
  <li>познайомитися із сучасними методами та інструментами наук про дані та машинного навчання, а також отримати практичні навички їх застосування;</li>
  <li>круто провести час у середовищі однодумців.</li>
</ul>

<p>Деталі на  <a href="https://sites.google.com/view/kau-dss2022/Main">сайті</a>.</p>

<h2 id="необхідний-рівень-знань-для-участі-у-школі">Необхідний рівень знань для участі у Школі:</h2>
<p>базові знання в галузі ІТ, обробки даних та початкові навички з програмування. Для участі у практичних заняттях потрібні попередні знання в галузі вищої математики та базові навички в програмуванні.</p>

<p>З нетерпінням чекаємо Вас на KAU Data Science School-2022!</p>

<p><strong>Дата і час</strong>: 12-13 березня 2022<br />
<strong>Місце проведення</strong>: online + offline (бульв. Академіка Вернадського 3б)<br />
<strong>Мова</strong>: українська<br />
<strong>Участь для студентів</strong> – <em>безкоштовна</em>. Для інших учасників діє реєстраційний внесок – <em>500 грн.</em><br />
<strong>Реєстрація обов’язкова за посиланням</strong>: <a href="https://forms.gle/LJL1CiKHmH7wXCKf8">https://forms.gle/LJL1CiKHmH7wXCKf8</a></p>]]></content><author><name>Alina Frolova</name></author><category term="opportunities" /><category term="all" /><category term="opportunities" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[З радістю повідомляємо, що KAU Data Science School повертається!]]></summary></entry></feed>